Jiasheng Gu

Homepage GitHub LinkedIn Email: jiashengguwen@gmail.com Phone: +86 17701621592

Research Interests

My research interest lies in the fields of natural language processing and generation, along with reliable and efficient methods for interconverting between natural language and different forms of data.

Long-term research goal: Use artificial intelligence to turn natural language into a bridge to various tasks.

Education

University of Southern California

Los Angeles, CA

Honor M.S. in Machine Learning and Data Science Aug. 2021 - May. 2023 Relevant Courses: Deep Learning, Probability, Linear Algebra, Parallel Computing *GPA: 4.0/4.0 (100%)*

Xidian University

Xian, Shaanxi

B.E. in Telecommunications Engineering Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2021

Relevant Courses: Data Structure, Calculus, Discrete Mathematics

GPA: 3.6/4.0 (90%, Top 10%)

Publications

Robustness of learning from task instructions

Jiasheng Gu, Hongyu Zhao, Hanzi Xu, Liangyu Nie, Hongyuan Mei, Wenpeng Yin ACL 2023 findings, *Arxiv*

Research Experience

North Carolina State University

• Mentors: Dongkuan Xu, Xipeng Shen

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Project: Zero-shot Code Generation via Rule-AI Co-learning from Document
- Contribution: Proposed a zero-shot code generation framework combining rulebased and AI-based methods to generate DSL code.
- Publication: EMNLP workshop in prep

Shanghai Jiaotong University

• Mentors: Pengfei Liu

April 2023 - June 2023

- Project: Training Large Language Model on Math Tasks
- Contribution: Trained(continue pretraining and finetune) LLaMA-13B on well-designed math datasets to improve the performance of math tasks.

University of Southern California

• Mentors: Peter A. Beerel

Aug. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- Project: Designing visual networks with very low FLOPs
- Contribution: Proposed a dilated depthwise convolution that captures global information and extensive experiments are done on it.

Pennsylvania State University

• Mentor: Wenpeng Yin

June. 2022 - Oct. 2022

- Project: Robustness of learning from task instructions
- Contribution: Experimented and analyzed the robustness of the instruction-tuned model on perturbed instructions.
- Publication: Arxiv

Dartmouth College

• Mentor: Soroush Vosoughi

May. 2022 - Sep. 2022

- Project: The Evolution of Artificial Intelligence in Bio-Medicine
- Contribution: Proposed a method to analyze artificial intelligence techniques used in biomedical publications.
- Publication: Under review, Journal of Medical Internet Research (JMIR)

University of Southern California

• Mentor: Pedro Szekely Filip Ilievski

Jan. 2022 - May. 2022

- Project: Integrating factual information from language models into knowledge graph embeddings
- Contribution: Improved link prediction task by factual information mined from language models via prompts.

ETH Zürich

• Mentor: Yuyi Wang

June. 2020 - Oct. 2020

- Project: Designing pre-training tasks for text summarization
- Contribution: Using trained metrics to find the highest-importance sentences as summaries makes the pre-training task more effective.

Industry Experience

Lime

• SDE internship

May. 2022 - Aug. 2022

 Refactored a system for timed feature extraction and computation for enhanced scalability. Optimized the process of timed computation, resulting in significant improvement in the overall system efficiency.

Transwarp

NLP internship

Jan. 2021 - Apr. 2021

Established a long text summarization system with an extractive-abstractive structure, with DGCNN for extractive summarization and BART for abstractive summarization.

Professional service

Program Committee

• The European Chapter of the ACL (EACL)

2023

ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining(WSDM)

2023

Association for Computational Linguistics(ACL)

2023 2023

• Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing

Teaching Experience

Teaching assistant, University of Southern California

• EE 503: Probability for Electrical and Computer Engineers

Fall 2022

• Grading course work and answering questions for students.

Awards

USC Ming Hsieh Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering

• Masters Students Honors Program

2021

Skills

Python, C++, C, R, Java, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, MATLAB

Framework

Programming

PyTorch, Tensorflow, OpenCV, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, SciPy

Professional Softwares

Git, LaTeX, SPSS, Mathematica, AWS, GCP, Docker, MongoDB

References

Wenpeng Yin, Assistant Professor

Computer Science and Engineering Department Pennsylvania State University wenpeng.yin@temple.edu

Dongkuan Xu, Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science North Carolina State University dxu27@ncsu.edu

Xipeng Shen, Professor

Department of Computer Science North Carolina State University xshen5@ncsu.edu

Pengfei Liu, Assistant Professor

Qing Yuan Research Institute Shanghai Jiaotong University stefanpengfei@gmail.com

Peter A. Beerel, Professor

Ming Hsieh Electrical and Computer Engineering Department University of Southern California pabeerel@usc.edu

Filip Ilievski, Assistant Professor

Viterbi School of Engineering University of Southern California ilievski@isi.edu

Soroush Vosoughi, Assistant Professor

Department of Computer Science Dartmouth College soroush.vosoughi@dartmouth.edu